George Shally Papers VHP2006/21
CCSU Veterans History Project
George Shally Papers
Bulk, 1942-1945
1942 - 1945, 2006
VHP2006/21
CCSU Veterans History Project
10.0 Digital objects 1 interview DVD
This collection details experience of George Shally as he served in the infantry, U.S. Army in Europe and Philippines during World War II. The collection contains video of an oral history interview along with discharge papers, and photographs.
Shally, George, 1926 -
Biographical/Historical note
George Shally enlisted in the United States Army in 1944 while he was in college in Berkeley, CA. He joined because he wanted to fight against the Nazi regime of Germany, and in the army he knew he would be able to serve in the infantry. Shally went to basic training in Florida, where they had to march 25 miles a day during the summer. He then transferred to California, where his division practiced invasions on a small island. When his infantry division shipped to the European theater, they began marching in France, and then marched all the way to Austria. In the infantry, Shally served as rifleman and first scout. He describes the conditions he faced when fighting in the Battle of the Bulge and other combat situations. After the war was declared over in Europe, he was transferred to the Pacific, where his division was going to take part in the invasion of Japan; however, the war was over before he could be transferred. He was sent to Luzon (Philippines) instead, where he rounded up Japanese soldiers who were unaware that the war had ended.. Shally was discharged in May of 1946, and when he returned home and finished college with the GI Bill.
Conditions Governing Access note
Open for Research
Custodial History note
All manuscripts and photographs donated were digitized and digitally preserved. The donor retained all original manuscripts and photographs.
Online Access
An online exhibition of this veteran's papers can be accessed at project's website
United States. Army. Infantry Division, 86th.; United States. Army. Infantry Regiment, 343rd.; Ardennes, Battle of the, 1944-1945; France; Germany; Luzon (Philippines); World War, 1939-1945; World War, 1939-1945 -- Campaigns -- Europe; World War, 1939-1945 -- Campaigns -- Philippines
- Series I: Personal Papers, VHP2006/21.I
  - Honorable Discharge certificate, May 17, 1946; VHP2006/21.I.1
  - Discharge paper, May 17, 1946; VHP2006/21.I.2
  - Interview synopsis, Mar. 16, 2006; VHP2006/21.I.3
- Series II: Multi-Media, VHP2006/21.II
  - Series A: Still Images, VHP2006/21.II
    - B29 bomber in the Philippines, between 1942 - 1945; VHP2006/21.II.1
    - George Shally(left)and unknown soldier, between 1942 - 1945; VHP2006/21.II.2
    - George Shally’s company after the war is over, Philippines., between 1942 - 1945; VHP2006/21.II.3
    - George Shally(left) and unknown soldier, Philippines, between 1942 - 1945; VHP2006/21.II.4
    - Unknown soldier posting with Curtiss P-40 fighter airplane, Philippines, between 1942 - 1945; VHP2006/21.II.5
    - George Shally smoking pipe, between 1942 - 1945; VHP2006/21.II.6
  - Series B: Moving Images, VHP2006/21.IIb
    - Oral history interview with George Shally, Mar. 19, 2006; VHP2006/21.IIb.1 (Disk DVD VHP2006/21, Box VHP Interview 2006)